Guide to the Sheila Danko papers, 1989-2014
Danko, Sheila papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sheila Danko papers, 1989-2014
23-16-4323
Sheila Danko
5. 8 cubic feet.
Artwork, course material, and biographical records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes Danko's dossier, Danko's entry to the Nagoya International Design Competition (1995), and student projects and slides from various courses Danko taught.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus in the Dept. of Design and Environmental Analysis, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes Danko's dossier, Danko's entry to the Nagoya International Design Competition (1995), and student projects and slides from various courses Danko taught.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Danko, Sheila; Danko, Sheila; Cornell University -- Faculty.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Design and Environmental Analysis.
Subjects:
Interior architecture -- Study and teaching.; Architecture, Domestic -- United States; Work environment -- Design.; Architecture -- Human factors; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Form and Genre Terms:
Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Series II. Course material
Series III. Awards
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical
  - Danko's dossier, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Course material
  - Designing change projects
    - Domini Social Investments, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Honest Tea, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Girls Explore, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Sunlight Electric, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - DucDuc NYC, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Share our Strength, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Dancing Deer Barking Company, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Pure Vida, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Three Twins Ice Cream, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Pret a Manager, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Maggie's Organic Clothing, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Immaculate Baking Company, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - DEA 1110
    - Making a difference by design, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Teaching assistant manual, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Course of Creativity
    - Five profiles prepared for the Foundation for Interior Design Education and Research, 1989; Danko, Sheila (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - DEA 499
    - Examples of senior studio projects, 2002-2009 (Box 2)
  - DEA 645
    - Examples of creative thinking toys, 2003-2005 (Box 3)
    - Slides of class projects for DEA 101; 102; 115; 301; 302; 499 and 645, 1982-1990 (Box 3)
      Slides
- Awards
  - Nagoya International Design Competition
    - Bronze prize entry, 1995; Dnako, Sheila (Box 4)
      Includes restorative composites: fiber and paint; fiber and vinyl; fiber and glue; fiber and plaster; fiber and ceramic; fiber and linoleum
    - Bronze prize entry, 1995; Dnako, Sheila (Box 5)